Guide to the International Association for Cultural Freedom Records 1941-1978
University of Chicago Library
International Association for Cultural Freedom. Records
1941-1978
349 linear feet (674 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
This collection contains the records of the Congress for Cultural Freedom and the International Association for Cultural Freedom. It comprises correspondence, reports, manuscripts, photographs, publications, recordings and clippings. It also includes the records of the Congress for Cultural Freedom affiliated Latin American Institute of International Relations and the Congress for Cultural Freedom Affiliated funded magazine Preuves. The collection dates from 1941-1978, with the bulk of the material dating from 1950-1972.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Historical Note
The Congress for Cultural Freedom was founded in 1950 as an anti-communist advocacy organization whose primary intention was to influence left leaning intellectuals and cultural leaders. Based in Paris, the CCF fielded dozens of offices across the world, and supported anti-communist cultural activities through publications, conferences, seminars, and funding of researchers, authors, poets, and artists. It included famous public intellectuals and artists such as Bertrand Russell, Karl Jaspers, Arthur Schlesinger, Jr. and Tennessee Williams.
In the 1960s, it became publicly known that the Congress for Cultural Freedom received funds from the CIA and that some members were CIA operatives. In response to this controversy, the Congress for Cultural Freedom was reorganized as the International Association for Cultural Freedom. Nicolas Nabokov, president, and John C. Hunt, executive director of the CCF, both resigned and Shepard Stone was named president of the IACF.
The IACF retained the mission and organizational structure of CCF under its new leadership. However, as funding for the IACF decreased during the 1970s and the nature of the Cold War changed, the scope of the organization decreased and by 1978 the last offices of the IACF had closed.
Scope Note
The International Association for Cultural Freedom Records are divided into eight series:
Series I, Correspondence Chronological File, 1953-1968 contains general correspondence related to the CCF and IACF.
Series II, Correspondence and Subject Files, 1948-1978 contains correspondence, reports, manuscripts and clippings filed topically by the Paris Office of the CCF and IACF.
Series III, Seminars, 1950-1977 documents the IACF's programs to encourage the work of intellectuals in all parts of the world by bringing together intellectuals, from regional or national areas or internationally, to consider specific issues or problems. The issues considered in the seminars ranged from Twentieth Century Masterpieces (Paris 1952), The Future of Freedom (Milan 1955), The New Metropolis in the Arab World (Cairo 1960), The East-West Music Encounter (Tokyo 1961), Inter-University Cooperation in West Africa (Freetown 1961), The Formation of Elites in Latin America (Montevideo 1965) to The Intellectual and Power (Aspen 1973). Two seminars will be of particular interest to those researching the history of the CCF: The Founding Conference (Berlin 1950) which articulated the organization's goals and a tenth anniversary celebration, Progress in Freedom (Berlin 1960), which produced considerable documentation on the accomplishments of the CCF's first ten years and which reaffirmed its mission for the 1960's.
Series IV, Financial Files, 1951-1968, documents the routine financial transactions of the CCF. It includes bank statements, receipts, royalty notices, memoranda, airline and other travel receipts, and other minor financial records. Most of the material is dated 1951-1966.
Series V, Documentation and Ephemeral Publications, 1950-1972, documents one of the major initiatives of the CCF and IACF and contains record copies of newsletters, pamphlets, photographs, illustrations, scrapbooks and recordings produced by the organizations. The records of the journal Preuves are in Series VII. Records of Der Monat, a German language journal associated at some points in its publication history with the IACF form a separate collection.
Series VI, Latin American Institute of International Relations (ILARI), 1954-1972, contains records associated with the Instituto LatinAmericano de Relaciones Internationales, a partner institute to the CCF, founded in Lima, Peru in 1965 under the directorship of Luis Mercier Vega. Among ILARI's primary goals was distribution of CCF publications in Latin America, and establishment of new centers for study, primarily in South America.
Series VII, Preuves Papers, 1951-1969 includes the records of Preuves, a journal sponsored by the CCF which appeared monthly between 1951 and 1969, had a closer relationship to the CCF than other sponsored journals because it was published in Paris, the Congress' headquarters. Its editorial policy was characterized by three areas of special interest: European intellectuals in relation to emergent European community; the situation and problems of intellectuals in communist states; and colonial wars and the consequences of decolonization.
Series VIII, Edward Shils Papers, 1958-1975, contains correspondence to and from Edward Shils.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Shils, Edward, 1910-1995; Congress for Cultural Freedom; International Association for Cultural Freedom; Anti-communist movements -- Europe; Europe -- Intellectual life -- 20th century
INVENTORY
- Series I: Correspondence Chronological File, 1953-1968
  Series I contains general correspondence related to the CCF and IACF, organized in an alphabetical sequence for each year from 1953 to 1968. Correspondence to and from Edward Shils may be found in Series VIII.
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence, 1953
    - A-B, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - C-E, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - F-J, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - K-L, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - M-O, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - P-R, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - S-U, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - V-Z, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2: Correspondence, 1954
    - A, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - B, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - C, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - D-F, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - G-H, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - I-K, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - L, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - M, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - N-O, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - P-Q, January-July, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - P-Q, August-December, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - R, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - S, January-June, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - S July-December, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - T-Z, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 3: Correspondence, 1955
    - A, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - B, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - C, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - D-E, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - F-G, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - H-K, January-June, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - H-K, July-December, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - L, January-July, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - M, January-June, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - N-O, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - P-Q, January-March, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - P-Q, April-June, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - P-Q, July-December, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - R, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - S, January-July, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - S, August-December, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - T-U, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - V-Z, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4: Correspondence, 1956
    - A, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - B, January-June, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - B, July-December, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - C, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - D, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - E-F, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - G, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - H, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - I-K, January-July, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - I-K, August-December, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - L, January-July, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - L, August-December, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - M, January-July, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - M, August-December, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - N-O, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - P-Q, January-March, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - P-Q, April-July, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - P-Q, August-December, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - R, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - S, January-April, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - S, May-July, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - S, August-December, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - T-U, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - V-Z, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 5: Correspondence, 1957
    - A, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - B, January-May, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - B, June-December, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - C, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - D, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - E, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - F, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - G, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - H, January-July, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - H, August-December, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - I, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - J, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - K, January-May, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - K, June-December, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - L, January-June, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - L, July-December, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - M, January-May, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - M, June-December, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - N-O, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - P, January-March, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - P, April-July, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - P, August-December, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Q-R, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - S, January-March, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - S, April-May, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - S, June-September, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - S, October-December, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - T, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - U-Z, January-May, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - U-Z, June-December, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 6: Correspondence, 1958
    - A, January-April, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - A, May-August, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - A, September-December, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - B, January-March, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - B, April-August, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - B, September-December, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - C, January-July, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - C, August-December, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - D, January-May, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - D, June-December, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - E, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - F, January-May, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - F, June-December, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - G, January-May, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - G, June-December, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - H, January-March, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - H, April-July, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - H, August-December, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - I, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - J, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - K, January-June, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - K, August-December, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - L, January-April, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - L, May-December, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - M, January-May, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - M, June-August, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - M, September-December, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - N, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - O, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - P, January-May, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - P, June-August, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - P, September-December, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Q-R, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - S, January-March, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - S, April-May, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - S, June-September, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - S, October-December, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - T, January-July, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - T, August-December, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - U-V, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - W-Z, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 7: Correspondence, 1959
    - A, January-July, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - A, August-December, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - B, January-June, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - B, July-December, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - C, January-June, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - C, July-December, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - D, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - E, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - F, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - G, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - H, January-June, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - H, July-December, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - I, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - J, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - K, January-July, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - K, August-December, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - L, January-June, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - L, July-December, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - M, January-April, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - M, May-August, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - M, September-December, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - N, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - O, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - P, January-April, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - P, May-September, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - P, October-December, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Q-R, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - S, January-March, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - S, April-July, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - S, August-October, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - S, November-December, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - T, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - U-V, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - W, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Y-Z, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 8: Correspondence, 1960
    - A, January-June, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - A, July-December, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - B, January-June, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - B, July-December, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - C, January-June, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - C, July-December, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - D, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - E, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - F, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - G, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - H, January-June, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - H, July-December, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - I, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - J, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - K, January-June, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - K, July-December, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - L, January-June, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - L, July-December, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - M, January-March, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - M, April-August, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - M, September-December, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - N, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - O-P, January-July, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - O-P, August-December, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Q-R, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - S, January-March, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - S, April-July, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - S, August-September, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - S, October-December, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - T, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - U-W, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - X-Z, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 9: Correspondence, 1961
    - A, January-April, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - A, May-December, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - B, January-April, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - B, May-August, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - B, September-December, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - C, January-April, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - C, May-December, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - D, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - E, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - F, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - G, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - H, January-June, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - H, July-December, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - I, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - J, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - K, January-June, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - K, July-December, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - L, January-June, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - L, July-December, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - M, January-April, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - M, May-September, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - M, October-December, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - N, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - O-P, September-December, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - P, May-August, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - P, January-April, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Q-R, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - S, January-March, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - S, April-June, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - S, July-September, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - S, October-December, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - T, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - U-V, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - W-Z, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 10: Correspondence, 1962
    - A, January-June (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - A, July-December (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - B, January-April (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - B, May-August (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - B, September-December (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - C, January-June (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - C, July-December (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - D, January-June (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - D, July-December (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - E-F (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - G (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - H, January-June (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - H, July-December (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - I (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - J, January-June (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - J, July-December (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - K, January-June (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - K, July-December (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - L, January-June (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - L, July-December (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - M, January-April (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - M, May-August (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - M, September-December (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - N (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - O (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - P, January-July (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - P, August-December (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Q-R (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - S, January-April (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - S, May-August (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - S, September-December (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - T (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - U-V (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - W-Z (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 11: Correspondence, 1963
    - A, January-June (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - A, July-December (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - B, January-February (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - B, March-April (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - B, May-June (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - B, July-August (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - B, September-December (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - C, January-May (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - C, June-December (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - D (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - E-F (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - G (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - H, January-June (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - H, July-December (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - I (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - J (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - K (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - L (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - M, January-April (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - M, May-August (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - M, September-December (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - N (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - O-P, July-December (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - P, January-June (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Q-R, July-December (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - R, January-June (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - S, January-April (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - S, May-August (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - S, September-December (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - T (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - U-V (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - W-Z (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 12: Correspondence, 1964
    - A, January-June (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - A, July-December (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - B, January-April (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - B, May-August (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - B, September-December (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - C, January-June (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - C, July-December (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - D (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - E-F (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - G (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - H, January-June (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - H, July-December (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - I (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - J, January-June (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - J, July-December (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - K (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - L (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - M, January-April (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - M, May-August (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - M, September-December (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - N (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - O-P July-December (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - P, January-June (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Q-R, July-December (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - R, January-June (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - S, January-April (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - S, May-August (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - S, September-December (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - T (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - U-V (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - W-Z (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 13: Correspondence, 1965
    - A, January-May (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - A, June-December (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - B, January-June (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - B, July-December (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - C, January-June (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - C, July-December (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - D (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - E-F (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - G (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - H (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - I (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - J, January-June (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - J, July-December (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - K (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - L (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - M, January-March (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - M, April-June (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - M, July-December (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - N-O (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - P (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Q-R, July-December (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - R, January-June (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - S, January-March (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - S, April-August (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - S, September-December (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - T (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - U-V (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - W-Z (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 14: Correspondence, 1966
    - A (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - B, January-June (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - B, July-December (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - C (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - D (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - E-F (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - G (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - H-I (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - J (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - K (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - L (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - M, January-May (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - M, June-December (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - N-O (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - P-Q (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - R (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - S, January-June (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - S, July-December (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - T-V (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - W-Z (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 15: Correspondence, 1967
    - A (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - B, January-June (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - B, July-December (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - C (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - D (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - E-F (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - G (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - H-I (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - J (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - K (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - L (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - M, January-June (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - M, July-December (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - N-O (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - P-Q (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - R (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - S, January-June (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - S, July-December (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - T-Z (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 16: Correspondence, 1968
    - A (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - B, January-June (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - B, July-December (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - C, January-June (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - C, July-December (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - D (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - E-F (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - G (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - H (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - I-J (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - K (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - L (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - M, January-June (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - M, July-December (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - N (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - O (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - P (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Q-R (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - S, January-April (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - S, May-August (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - S, September-December (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - T-U (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - V-Z (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Original packing lists prepared by the Paris office in transferring the IACF Archive to the University of Chicago (Box 54, Folder 8)
- Series II: Correspondence and Subject Files